# **Donald Hyde**

Bowdoin, ME 04287 760.492.4726 donald.hyde2@gmail.com https://github.com/donaldhyde https://www.linkedin.com/in/donaldhyde

# FRONT-END DEVELOPER

Front-end Developer with eight years experience developing responsive web applications through each stage of the software development lifecycle using Agile methodologies. Skilled collaborator knows how to sync with product, design, and other engineers to create excellent user experiences and write high-performance, easily maintained code.

#### **KEY SKILLS**

Javascript | HTML | CSS | React | MongoDB | PHP | WordPress

Agile Development | Unit Testing | Responsive Design | User Experience

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### Ingage (Previously ScrollMotion) - San Diego, CA

Transforming sales with industry-leading interactive presentation software.

# **Product Manager**

October 2018 - January 2019

Defined and prioritized feature roadmap to deliver high-value products aligned with business needs and goals.

- Reviewed designs and requirements for new features and wrote corresponding user stories.
- Managed product backlog and identified highest-value items for upcoming sprints.
- Coached iOS development team in Agile best practices resulting in completion of sprint backlogs.
- Collaborated with test team to cut regression testing from three days to four hours.
- Facilitated Scrum ceremonies for development team distributed across the U.S. and in Brazil.

#### **Web Development Manager**

September 2017 - October 2018

Managed high-performance team in the development and delivery of all company web technology.

- Advocated self-organization methods to achieve accurate estimates and maximize sprint execution.
- Increased team output by coaching developers on when and how to prioritize speed over quality.
- Oversaw code structure and maintainability through regular code reviews and pull requests.
- Identified technical challenges in UI/UX designs and collaborated on solutions.
- Communicated technical concepts to non-technical stakeholders.

### **Front-End Developer**

August 2014 - September 2017

Developed web applications and websites with Agile development methodologies.

- Interpreted design specs into requirements for user stories, translated requirements to React code.
- Synchronized development efforts across functional teams, limiting deployment delays.
- Directed onboarding and training of new and junior engineers.
- Implemented analytics for company websites and software using Mixpanel and Google Analytics.
- Developed custom WordPress themes and landing pages.
- Created cross-browser, cross-platform in-line text editing experience.
- Led transition of large enterprise codebase into legacy software and continued maintenance thereafter.

# **WORK EXPERIENCE** (Continued)

# TV Page - San Diego, CA

Changing online retail with shoppable video storefronts.

# Front-End Developer

Developed web applications and internal frameworks.

• Built templates for web-embeddable video player.

#### Ingage (Previously ScrollMotion) - San Diego, CA

# **Front-End Developer**

February 2011 - February 2014

March 2014 - July 2014

Built large-scale web applications in an agile environment.

- Designed and built browser-based children's book authoring tool—build on the web, deploy to iOS.
- Built two versions of the authoring tool, SmartStudio, based on design specifications—build once, publish to iOS, Android, and Windows
- Developed custom data query API for proprietary data format.
- Wrote conversion scripts to support data versioning upgrades, giving users access to the latest release.
- Improved code coverage by writing unit tests for new and existing code using Jasmine.
- Strengthened customer support across the company by teaching users how to use SmartStudio software.

#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

Professional Scrum Product Owner (PSPO I) - Scrum.org Professional Scrum Master (PSM I) - Scrum.org

## **EDUCATION**

### Bachelor of Arts - Creative Writing & English, 2019

Southern New Hampshire University, Manchester, NH